Okay, we've talked about user consistency and ethical considerations.
好的 我们已经讨论了用户一致性和伦理方面的考虑因素
What's the third thing to keep in mind?
第三个注意事项是什么？
>> The third thing to keep in mind is variability.
第三个注意事项是差异性
Now, you might recall back in lesson three,
回忆一下第三课
we talked about how to compute the variability of a metric empirically.
我们曾提到如何根据经验计算指标的差异性
And that the reason why was because sometimes the empirically computed
当时我们给出的理由是 因为根据经验计算得出的差异性
variability was much higher than the analytically computed variability.
有时会远远高于根据分析方法计算得出的差异性
Now the reasoning for this is because that's what happens when your unit of
现在我们的理由是 因为当分析单元不同于分组单元时
analysis is different than your unit of diversion.
这种现象很常见
Now, what's the unit of analysis?
什么是分析单元？
The unit of analysis is basically whatever the denominator
分析单元就是
of your metric is.
指标的分母
So for example, if you're doing click through rate, and you have
例如 在计算点击率指标时
clicks divided by page views then page view would be your unit of analysis.
你用点击量除以页面查看量 那么页面查看量就是你的分析单元
Now, when your unit of diversion is also a page view, so as would be the case
如果分组单元也是页面查看
in an event base diversion, then the analytically computed variability
例如在分组单元为事件的例子中 那么根据分析方法计算的差异性
is likely to be very close to the empirically computed variability.
可能很接近根据经验计算的差异性
If, however, your unit of diversion is a cookie or a user id then the variability
然而 如果分组单元是 cookie 或用户 ID
of your same metric click through rate is actually going to be much higher.
那么点击率指标的差异性就会大得多
Sometimes by a factor of four, five, maybe even more.
可能会相差四到五倍 甚至更多
And in those cases you really want to move to an empirically
在使用这些分组单元时
computed variability given your unit of diversion.
你可能会倾向于根据经验计算差异性
>> Wow, why does that make such a big difference?
为什么会有这么大的差异？
>> So what happens is that when you're actually computing your variability
根据分析方法计算差异性时
analytically, you're fundamentally making an assumption
你需要对数据的分布情况
about the distribution of the data.
作一个假设
But you're not just making an assumption
然而 在作这个假设时 你不仅仅在假设数据的分布情况
You're also making an assumption about what's considered to be independent.
你还在假设哪些事物具有独立性
You're basically doing these random draws and
因此 你实际上是在随机抽签
whether they're independent or not.
并据此判断事物的独立性
When you're doing event-based diversion every single event is a different random
如果分组单元是事件 那么你需要为每个事件进行一次随机抽签
draw, and so your independence assumption is actually valid.
从而你的独立性假设实际上是有效的
Now when you're doing cookie or user ID based diversion,
如果分组单元是 cookie 或用户 ID
that independence assumption is no longer valid because you're actually
你所作的独立性假设就是无效的
diverting groups of events.
因为你已经将事件分组
And so they're actually correlated together.
它们之间实际上已存在某种关系
And that will increase your variability greatly.
这种关系可能导致差异性大大升高